Finding Aid for Gunnar Birkerts papers 1930-2002
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
- Professional Papers
  - Transcripts and Notes of Speeches, Lectures and Seminars
    - Academic Institutions
      - University of Michigan-316 Studio Lecture, March 4, 1986 (Box 1)
      - Ohio State University-"Virtue of Individuality,", April 23, 1986 (Box 1)
      - University of Michigan Brown Bag, March 24, 1987 (Box 1)
      - Ball State University College of Architecture & Planning Summer Workshop, Columbus, Indiana-"Saarinen Legacy,", June 2, 1987 (Box 1)
      - Ball State University College of Architecture & Planning Summer Workshop, Columbus, Indiana-"Organic Architecture-The Steady Core of the Modern Movement,", June 4, 1987 (Box 1)
      - University of Michigan-"Continuity,", October 7, 1987 (Box 1)
      - University of Michigan-"The Organic Does Not Deconstruct,", January 12, 1989 (Box 1)
        #
      - Tubinger Kunstgeschichtliche Gesellschaft & Architektenkammer-"Appropriateness and Meaning-The Architecture of Gunnar Birkerts,", October 25, 1989 (Box 1)
      - University of Michigan-John Dinkeloo Memorial Lecture-"The Virtue of Being Serious,", March 1, 1990 (Box 1)
      - California Polytechnic State University, May 3, 1990 (Box 1)
      - University of Oklahoma-Bruce Goff Professorship Series
        - Lecture I, October 31, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Lecture II-"Organic Architecture,", November 13, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"Nature of Imagination,", October 16, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"Necessity for Design Process,", October 16, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Jim Kudrna Seminar-"Introduction to Education,", October 16, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"The Act of Representation,", October 30, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"Society and Self,", November 5, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"Eero Saarinen Slide Show,", November 5, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Theory Seminar, November 13, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Jim Kudrna Theory Seminar, November 13, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Jim Kudrna Third Year Seminar, November 15, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"Context, Site, etc,", November 15, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"Means, Materials and Structure,", December 5, 1990 (Box 1)
        - Elinor Weinel Seminar-"The Role of Critique,", December 6, 1990 (Box 1)
      - University of Wisconsin, Milwaukee-"Polygonal/Underground,", March 25, 1992 (Box 1)
      - Kansas City Art Institute-Commencement Speech, May 9, 1992 (Box 1)
      - Ohio State University College of Law, March 5-6, 1993 (Box 1)
      - Reflective Studio Seminar, March 13, 1993 (Box 1)
      - Lawrence Technological University-"Expression,", April 1, 1993 (Box 1)
      - Ohio State University and Millikin University-"Unclassifiable Architecture,", circa 1995-1996 (Box 1)
      - Louisiana Technological School of Architecture-William B. Wiener Memorial Lecture-"Unclassifiable Architecture,", March 25, 1997 (Box 1)
      - University of Michigan-Lecture for "Between Earth and Sky" Exhibit Opening, October 18, 1999 (Box 1)
      - Michigan Technological University, October 4, 2000 (Box 1)
    - Professional Associations and Public Audiences
      - "Glass-Poetry and Metaphor in Building Design," no place or date noted (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous Lecture Notes, unidentified, undated (Box 2)
      - Great Lakes NOFA Conference, Dearborn, MI -- "Interior Design in the Modern Office,", May 4, 1957 (Box 2)
      - National Council on Schoolhouse Construction (NCSC) Regional Meeting, Ball State University-"Plans for Tougaloo College,", April 17, 1967 (Box 2)
      - SCARAB National Convention, University of Illinois-"Appropriateness in Architecture,", November 21, 1967 (Box 2)
      - Architecture and the College Conference, University of Illinois-"Design for a Developing Campus In the South (Tougaloo College),", May 1, 1968 (Box 2)
      - Minneapolis Institute of Arts Lecture, October 15, 1969 (Box 2)
      - Speech Note Cards
        - Tau-Sigma-Delta Honor Society National Convention, June 20, 1971 (Box 2)
        - Minnesota Society of Architects Meeting-Federal Reserve Bank, March 28, 1974 (Box 2)
        - Arts Foundation of Michigan, undated (Box 2)
        - Five speeches, undated (Box 2)
      - Association of Student Chapters of AIA 20th Annual Convention, Columbus, Indiana, November 26, 1976 (Box 2)
      - Minnesota Society AIA Convention, September 7, 1978 (Box 2)
      - Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture, Western Regional Conference, Tempe, AZ-"Hi-Tech Architecture,", October 6, 1979 (Box 2)
      - Speech Template, circa 1982-1983 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous Lectures, circa 1982-1988 (Box 2)
      - The Smithsonian Institution Resident Associate Program, April 26, 1983 (Box 2)
      - Urban Center Books Forums on Form (Municipal Art Society of New York), June 1, 1983 (Box 2)
      - Iowa AIA Convention, September 14, 1983 (Box 2)
      - Omaha Chapter AIA Annual State Meeting, September 21, 1984 (Box 2)
      - University of Michigan Alumni Meeting-"Objectives and Manifestations of the Domino's Farms Project,", October 12, 1984 (Box 2)
      - University of Michigan Symposium-"Architectural Library of the Future,", January 23, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Stockholm Lecture, July 21, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Central States Region, AIA Convention, Omaha, October 16, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Ann Arbor AIA Meeting-Domino's Farms, November 5, 1987 (Box 2)
      - The Smithsonian Institution-"Organic Core of the Modern Movement,", November 16, 1987 (Box 2)
      - Speech Template, 1987 (Box 2)
      - State Capital Presentation, Lansing, Michigan, February 2, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Toledo Lecture-"Continuity,", February 9, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Steelcase Lecture, Grand Rapids, Michigan-"Power of the Mind,", November 15, 1988 (Box 2)
      - Mid-Florida Chapter AIA Meeting, Orlando, November 16, 1989 (Box 2)
      - Grand Valley Chapter AIA Meeting, Grand Rapids, Michigan, February 12, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Speech Templates, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Minnesota Society AIA and Walker Art Center Summer Design Series-"Federal Reserve Bank Retrofit,", July 18, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Nordic Baltic Architecture Triennial-Lecture/Synopsis, September 24, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Miscellaneous Lectures, circa 1990 (Box 2)
      - Charleston Lecture, September 20, 1991 (Box 2)
      - Birkerts Symposium, Riga, Latvia, January 28, 1992 (Box 2)
      - AIA Conferences-Indianapolis, North Dakota and Utah, 1992 (Box 2)
      - Los Angeles Lecture-"Process and Expression,", May 21, 1993 (Box 2)
      - Boulder, Colorado Lecture, October 15, 1993 (Box 2)
      - Milwaukee Lecture, "Design Process", October 7, 1994 (Box 2)
      - Saarinen/Swanson Reunion, Cranbrook-Remarks regarding Eero Saarinen, 1995 (Box 2)
      - New Zealand Institute of Architects Lecture, Dunedin, NZ, August 29, 1996 (Box 2)
      - Delft Underground Workshop, March 19, 1997 (Box 2)
      - Modena, Italy Lecture, October, 1997 (Box 2)
    - Building Dedications
      - Also available on audiotape (Box 2)
      - Also available on videocassette (Box 2)
      - University of Michigan Law Library Addition, October 31, 1981 (Box 2)
      - Domino's Farms, December 5, 1985 (Box 2)
      - University of Iowa College of Law, November 20, 1986 (Box 2)
      - University of California at San Diego Library Groundbreaking, March 4, 1990 (Box 2)
      - Kemper Museum of Contemporary Art and Design Groundbreaking, September 11, 1992 (Box 2)
      - Church of the Servant, Grand Rapids, Michigan, February 13, 1994 (Box 2)
      - Ohio State University College of Law Building Addition, May 1, 1993 (Box 2)
      - Duke University Law School Addition, April 8, 1995 (Box 2)
      - Michigan Technological University Performing Arts Center, October 4, 2000 (Box 2)
  - Transcripts of Interviews
    The second sub-series within the Professional Papers series, Transcripts of Interviews, relates to interviews given by Birkerts from 1982 to 2000. The interviews tend to focus on his professional career, his design philosophy and creative process, or a particular project on which he was working at the time. Some of the interviews (noted by an *) can be heard on the corresponding audiotapes, which are listed in the Audio-Visual Materials subseries. The researcher should be aware that additional interviews can be found in the Sources Used for Publication subseries.
    - Gregg Yeomans for Dichotomy (University of Detroit), May 1982 (Box 2)
    - "Gunnar Birkerts Interviewed by G.B." for Reflections (University of Illinois), Fall 1983; December 1982 (Box 2)
    - Charles Gandee for Architectural Record, January 10, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Charles Mertz-Regarding Detroit and Midwest Heritage, January 11, 1983 (Box 2)
    - Robert A. Benson-Regarding Domino's Farms Master Plan, June 20, 1984 (Box 2)
    - Diana Lennon for Detroit Free Press-"Taste,", July 29, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Jim Schwartz, November 6, 1986 (Box 2)
    - Andrea Dean (phone interview), 1986 (Box 2)
    - Robert A. Benson for Inland Architect-"An Interview with Gunnar Birkerts,", January-February 1986 (Box 2)
    - Jim Schwartz for Engineering News Record, January 6, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Bob Bauer for Michigan Alumnus-"Creativity,", September 30, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Kathy Blair for Ann Arbor News, December 29, 1987 (Box 2)
    - Yasser Mansour, January 16, 1988 (Box 2)
    - Ted Sandstra for Dialogue (Calvin College Journal), March 14, 1994 (Box 2)
    - Kay Kaiser for World Architecture, May 1994 (Box 2)
    - Bill Lacy-Regarding Purchase College, SUNY Master Plan, June 19, 1996 (Box 2)
    - Riga, Latvia, Interview-"Arhitekturaj Jabut Laikmetigai Nevis Modernai,", August 2000 (Box 2)
    - Unidentified Interview regarding Italian Period, undated (Box 2)
  - Audio-Visual Materials
    The third Professional Papers sub-series, Audio-Visual Materials, contains over 180 audiotapes and 22 videotapes of Birkerts' various speeches, lectures, interviews and musings. The tapes are arranged in chronological order and cover more than a thirty year period (1965-1998). Many of the tapes (noted by an * or a #) have corresponding transcripts and/or speaking notes in the Speeches, Lectures and Seminars, Interviews, and Sources Used for Publication sub-series.
    - Audiotapes of Speeches, Lectures and Interviews
      - 1965-1979
        - Lawrence Technological University Lecture, February 6, 1965; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - University of Arkansas Lecture, April 10-11, 1969; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - University of Michigan Lecture, February 26, 1970 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - University of Michigan Lecture-"Quo Vadis,", 1974 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - IBM Southfield-Energy Seminar (side A), November 1976 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - University of Michigan Brown Bag Lecture (side B), October 1976 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - New York Institute of Technology Lecture (side A), April 25, 1977 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - WCAR Interview with Aurora Hendricks-IBM Southfield (side B), 1977 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - University of Nebraska Lecture, November 10, 1977 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - Civita Seminar/University of Michigan-"Visualize," (side A), 1977 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - "Mind-Left Side, Right Side," (side B), 1977 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - Monograph Dictation (side A), circa 1978 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - University of Michigan Seminar-"Mind" and "Methodology," (side B), January 15, 1978 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - Dictations of Letters (side A), 1978 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - Columbia University Lecture (side B), March 1978 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - Autonomous University of Guadalajara Seminar, February 19-20, 1979; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
        - Autonomous University of Guadalajara Seminar-Questions and Answers, February 22, 1979 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 1)
      - 1979-1982
        - Louisiana State University Lecture (side A), September 25, 1979 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - Association of Collegiate Schools of Architecture Lecture (side B), October 6, 1979 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Faculty Design Meeting, October 30, 1979 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Seminar-"Knowing Yourself, Your Mind," (side A), September 1980 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Seminar-"Second Part Mind, First Part Design Methodology," (side B), September 1980 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Design Methodology Seminar, 1980 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Kentucky Lecture (side A), October 6, 1980 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Design Seminar-"Conceptualization," (side B), November 1980 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Seminar, 1980 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan Brown Bag Lecture-"Design Methodology,", February 9, 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan-Methodology I Seminar, September 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan-Methodology I Seminar (side A), September 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan-Methodology II Seminar (side B), 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Pennsylvania Lecture (side A), October 21, 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - T. Wolfe Seminar-"From Our House to Bauhaus," (side B), circa 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - Pratt Institute Lecture (side A), December 4, 1981 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Detroit Lecture (side B), January 29, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Oklahoma Lecture (side A), April 6, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - Impromptu Lecture-Ann Arbor (side B), April 12, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - Ball State University Lecture, April 14, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan-First Day Remarks and Dictation of Letters, Fall 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
        - University of Michigan-Methodology Seminar, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 2)
      - 1982-1983
        - University of Michigan Seminar-"You and Your Mind,", 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - University of Michigan ACSA Lecture, October 21, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - University of Michigan Seminar-"Metaphor, Symbolism and Color" (goes with lecture "Symbolism and Metaphor") (side A), November 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - Cranbrook School Lecture (side B), November 4, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - Texas A & M University Lecture, November 18, 1982 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - Charles Gandee Interview for Architectural Record, January 10, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - Charles Mertz Interview-Detroit Heritage/Midwest, January 11, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
        - University of Illinois-Plym Lecture Series
          - Lecture I, January 24, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
          - Lecture II, January 31, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
          - Lecture III-Metamorphosis Design Methodology (tape labeled "Design Metamorphosis 1959-Now"), February 14, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
          - Seminar I-"You and Your Mind, Knowing Yourself" (tape labeled "Revised Plym Lecture I"), February 18, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
          - Bob DeHaven's Theory Seminar, April 19, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
          - Faculty Colloquium I, January 26, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
          - Faculty Colloquium II, February 15, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 3)
      - 1983
        - University of Illinois-Plym Lecture Series (cont.)
          - Faculty Colloquium III, March 15, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
          - Forum I, February 9, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
          - Forum II, February 23, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
          - Forum III (Paulsen-Creese), March 14, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
          - Forum IV, April 13, 1983; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
        - Ball State University-Telecon "Lunchline,", March 15, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
        - Illinois Institute of Technology Lecture, April 5, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
        - The Smithsonian Institution Lecture, April 26, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
        - Iowa State University Lecture, May 9, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
        - Urban Center Books Lecture (Municipal Art Society of New York), June 1, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 4)
      - 1983-1984
        - Pavia, Italy Lecture, July 21, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Charles Merz Interview on Saarinen (side A), August 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Marsha Miro Interview-"Baldwin," for Detroit Free Press, (side B), August 29, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan-First Day Seminar, "Fading," (side A), September 12, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan-Student Seminar, "Methodology/Yourself," (side B), September 26, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Iowa AIA Convention Speech, September 14, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
          (date on tape is October 14, 1983)
        - Louisiana State University Lecture, November 29, 1983 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan Lecture-"Next Architecture,", February 13, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan Lecture-"Next Architecture-You and Your Mind/Methodology," (side A), March 5, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Texas Tech University Lecture-"Next Architecture, My Work," (side B), April 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Idaho and Washington State University Seminars, April 26, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Robert Benson's Class on Eero Saarinen, May 7, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Birmingham-Bloomfield Art Association Lecture, June 4, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Robert Benson Interview-Regarding Domino's Farms Master Plan, June 20, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - Robert Benson Interview-Domino's Farms, September 1, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan Seminar-"Design Methodology-Knowing Yourself,", September 17, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan-Monaghan Lecture, October 1, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
        - University of Michigan Alumni Meeting-"Objectives and Manifestations of the Domino's Farms Project,", October 12, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 5)
      - 1979, 1984-1986
        - Virginia Tech Lecture-"Departures,", November 7, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Michigan-T. S. Monaghan Lecture-"Concepts and Manifestations,", November 12, 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - "Thoughts to Kay Kaiser Regarding Writing,", 1984 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - Andrews University Lecture, April 18, 1985; 2 audiotapes (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - Benson IV Interview, August 19, 1985 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Michigan Lecture-"The Virtue of Individuality,", September 23, 1985 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Cincinnati Lecture, October 1, 1985 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - Colorado Springs AIA Lecture, October 10, 1985 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Michigan-Honors Studio Seminar-"Design Methodology I and II,", 1985 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - Architecture and Urbanism Essay-1500 words, 1985 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - Montana State University Lecture-"Virtue of Individuality,", January 23, 1986 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Michigan-316 Studio Lecture (side A), March 4, 1986 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - Saarinen Office History (side B), 1979 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Texas Lecture-"Virtue of Individuality,", March 12, 1986 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
        - University of Michigan Panel on "Yama"-G. Olving, K. Brown, W. Jarrett, G. Birkerts, March 17, 1986 (Box 3, Othertype Con. 6)
      - 1986-1987
        - Tamama Interview on Japan TV-Corning Museum of Glass, March 25, 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Ohio State University Lecture-"Virtue of Individuality," (side A), April 23, 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Frank Lloyd Wright Symposium Press Conference with T. S. Monaghan and Professor Bruno Zevi (side B), April 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - London Glass Conference-Lecture and Panel Discussion, April 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - London Glass Conference-Sum-Up, with T. S. Buechner, April 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Diana Lennon Interview for Detroit Free Press, July 29, 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Jim Schwartz Interview, November 6, 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Wisconsin AIA Lecture, November 7, 1986 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Papal Visit Interviews-Channel 4, Rich Myke, Pontiac Silverdome, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Jim Schwartz Interview for Engineering News Record, January 6, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - University of Michigan Symposium-"Architectural Library of the Future,", January 23, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - University of Michigan Brown Bag Lecture-"How to Get a Job,", March 16, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - University of Michigan Lecture by Vincent Scully on Frank Lloyd Wright, April 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - University of Michigan Brown Bag Lecture-"Metaphor" Seminar, April 29, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Ball State University College of Architecture & Planning Summer Workshop, Columbus, Indiana-"Saarinen Legacy,", June 2, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
        - Ball State University College of Architecture & Planning Summer Workshop, Columbus, Indiana-"Organic Architecture-The Steady Core of the Modern Movement,", June 4, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 7)
      - 1987-1988
        - State Capital Presentation, Lansing, Michigan, June 18, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Gordon Bugbee Interview, June 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Bob Bauer Interview for Michigan Alumnus-"Creativity,", September 30, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - University of Michigan Lecture-"Continuity,", October 7, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - AIA Omaha Convention Panel Discussion: H. N. Jacobson, Gibbs, G. Birkerts, Rose, October 1987; 2 audiotapes (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Ann Arbor Township Meeting-Domino's Tower, October 11, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Ann Arbor AIA Meeting-Domino's Farms, November 5, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - The Smithsonian Institution Lecture-"Organic Core of the Modern Movement,", November 16, 1987 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Kathy Blair Interview for Ann Arbor News, December 29, 1987; 2 audiotapes (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Interview with Student Jan Iversen-"How Gunnar Birkerts Approaches Structure,", January 7, 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - "Creativity, Subconscious, etc," (side A), January 16, 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - Yasser Mansour Interview (side B), January 16, 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - State Capital Restoration Master Plan Presentation, Lansing, Michigan-R. Frank and G. Birkerts (tape dated January 2, 1988), February 2, 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
        - University of Michigan Honors Studio-"You and Your Mind,", October 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 8)
      - 1988-1991, undated
        - Yasser Mansour Interview, October 15, 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 9)
        - Mississippi State University-Tele-Interview, October 20, 1988 (Box 4, Othertype Con. 9)